<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on Jean Rintoul</title>
    <link>https://jeanrintoul.github.io/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on Jean Rintoul</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 15:59:13 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jeanrintoul.github.io/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing Death</title>
      <link>https://jeanrintoul.github.io/blog/third/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeanrintoul.github.io/blog/third/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/18hRgzL7q7ZwtBRoBA-EeNuiFvFTp1SpPjqHObXLaTuk/embed?start=true&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;389&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this presentation for a weekend futurist getaway where everyone gives talks about their topic of interest. With so much focus on overcoming death, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take the naturalist perpective for a moment and look at the evolutionary advantages of death, integrating machine learning models to support their claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major rebuttal to my arguments were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that my quantized model of individuality limits how many memories we can store. Why not store all information ever experienced in highest resolution?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My answer is similar to why too many regulations slow down innovation. Why do we care about garbage collecting? There comes a point where information is no longer relevant. The individual doesn&amp;rsquo;t need it. It&amp;rsquo;s fine if the collective conscious stores an archived memory of it(historical documents in a library) that we can refer to, but I am glad this information is stored elsewhere. The &amp;lsquo;individual&amp;rsquo; should be agile, ever changing in the most dynamic way possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I ensure goodness or prevent the evil AI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>