<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transhumanism on Jean Rintoul</title>
    <link>https://jeanrintoul.github.io/tags/transhumanism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transhumanism on Jean Rintoul</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 15:59:13 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jeanrintoul.github.io/tags/transhumanism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing Death</title>
      <link>https://jeanrintoul.github.io/blog/third/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeanrintoul.github.io/blog/third/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/18hRgzL7q7ZwtBRoBA-EeNuiFvFTp1SpPjqHObXLaTuk/embed?start=true&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;389&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this presentation for a weekend futurist getaway. With so much focus currently on overcoming death, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take the naturalist perpective for a moment and look at the evolutionary advantages of death, while integrating machine learning models to support their claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I argue that death is necessary, and a futuristic version of death would be to die a little each day(and be born a little each day). Over a period of time all of you would die and a new you(including massive brain restructures and new limbs) would come into being.
This is less resource intensive than the current natural &amp;lsquo;starting from scratch&amp;rsquo; system we have going, while escaping the other option of simply living forever and gaining complexity into eternity. It avoids overtraining, and enables evolution within life, instead of by creating new life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two major rebuttals of my arguments after I gave the talk and I discuss them here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surely it&amp;rsquo;s best to store all information you&amp;rsquo;ve ever experienced instead of removing it from your being? More information is better yes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I disagree, better information is better. Too many regulations slow down innovation. There comes a point where information is no longer relevant. The individual doesn&amp;rsquo;t need it and it&amp;rsquo;s a burden to search and carry it with us. It&amp;rsquo;s fine if the collective conscious stores an archived memory of it(historical documents in a library/internet) that we can refer to in deep searches, but to be maximally dynamic/agile both mentally and physically we should limit ourselves to on information storage. Garbage collection(DEATH) is important. Memory capacity is important and select memories from all history and now should be kept and weighted according to their importance and independence from time. The game of Go is complex with only 4 rules, if you can distill life to deep underlying principles that are timeless, you can afford shorter memory capacity. Processing power(focus of attention) is key to be able to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I ensure goodness in my future self or prevent the evil AI? I want to put in safeguards so that my future self is moral.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I disagree and give up control to my future self - they can make moral decisions at the time. In the past it was the right thing to do to kill your own meat in order to survive, but in future this may be seen as evil. &amp;lsquo;Goodness&amp;rsquo; is subjective and must change with the environment one exists in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming self-selection bias.</title>
      <link>https://jeanrintoul.github.io/blog/fourth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeanrintoul.github.io/blog/fourth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Self-selection bias is when those in power select those more like themselves, which in turn heightens their own power. It is what makes power and value different. It&amp;rsquo;s the historical lag of power dynamics. It&amp;rsquo;s why England&amp;rsquo;s sea fleets led to white supremicist ideals in the US today. It&amp;rsquo;s the reason for patriarchy, slavery of racially different groups, and international borders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a group has power, those in power selects itself for its own preservation, seemingly becoming stronger and stronger - is it an unbeatable force? Potentially, yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who is not in the power group, it is difficult to come to terms with being limited by these superficial laws. Should my skin color really matter when it comes to a contribution in mathematics? Right now, it does. Should my gender matter when being considered for a promotion? Apparently yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free market argument:
Is the most competitive solution is enabled when gender/race is valued ahead of results in a specific area. The answer is no, though this has to be tempered with the fact that money is available to those of the correct race and gender more readily to garner value from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ML Argument:
&amp;lsquo; If you train on bad data you get bad results&amp;rsquo;. So if those in the highest power have biases not related to value, they will propagate them throughout the rest of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long Term Argument: The problem with capitalism isn&amp;rsquo;t that money is evil, it&amp;rsquo;s that money doesn&amp;rsquo;t represent value.
Power dynamics create lag in the economy, since power holds on for the sake of itself. Hence money and value are decoupled. If they were not decoupled capitalism would be a force for good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-implosion Argument:
Self-selection leaeds to large corporations so fat and full of themselves they are ineffective. We get governments that make poor choices, we get a general weakening of the self-selecting group because they are not selecting for value. They cannot be brought down by others, but they weaken themselves due to self-selection not value selection. This is a very slow effect however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal Escape Routes:
no 1.
Power is proportional to money in our capitalistic society. So one escape route is to find a method to profit without dealing with other people who are afflicted with value biases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;no 2.:
Take advantage of these comparative difference in the economy and hire cheaper better employees like women in India, etc. The problem with this is that there are communication gaps, and aspects of team comradery are missing. Perhaps VR can make remote workforces more effective?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global Escape Routes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make communication over large distances and between languages easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make the tools required to influence others be free. De-centralize media control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia and other free educational resources, the internet are enablers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access to online communities if individuals cannot meet in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom rung of Maslow&amp;rsquo;s hierarchy should be made as close to, if not completely free. Health, food, shelter should also be &amp;lsquo;democratized&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to do this as these things do have time/effort cost to implement and why would you spend your life keeping up with people&amp;rsquo;s breeding choices to make more resource intensive beings?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Population control: only have planned children, when financially ready and able. No child marriages, and don&amp;rsquo;t have more than 2 children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extend health and longevity so people are productive longer, but don&amp;rsquo;t spend money on end of life care when death is imminent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Net effect: fewer more educated, healthier people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these changes are very long term, short term changes are the save yourself model only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minorities should help themselves, support each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contribute to open projects that give value to others who have needs in the bottom of Maslow&amp;rsquo;s Hierarchy. In other words, let those in need help themselves and help each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Power is the ability to get your own way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>